RUEI-PU(Allen) KOU

imakou@gmail.com (preference) I (905)-966-3228 I Works - git.io/v5USD

3+ solid experiences in HTML/CSS including RWD, SPA. Familiar with popular front-end frameworks like Bootstrap, ReactJs and testing tools such as Mocha and end-to-end testing by Selenium. I have experience in developing a medium project as an F2E and I was responsible for implementing pages from mockup and rendering data from RESTful API services. I use some tools such as Git and Docker to enhance my performance of development, and I have experience with the Serverless structure (AWS' Lambda and API Gateway).

Skills

- 3+ yrs HTML / CSS (Sass)
- 2+ yrs JavaScript
- 1yr+ React/ Redux(Es6)
- 1yr+ NodeJs(Express, socket.io)
- Mocha ◆ Selenium ◆ Serverless
- Webpack Gulp Git Docker

Work experiences

Front End Developer I University of Waterloo - Conrad Business Centre

Waterloo, Canada I May 2017 - Aug 2017

- Implemented features based on React and Redux
- Practiced features including dynamic data graph, real-time chatting (Twilio's API)
- Built BDD testing practices (e2e by Cucumber, Selenium and Mocha)
- · Cooperated with UI/UX team and enhanced website's components to be better

Front End Developer | DIGIM

Taipei, Taiwan I January 2014 to May 2014

- · Developed retina display friendly RWD pages
- · Collaborated with the creative and back-end teams
- Enhanced colleagues' developing performances by using Sass and HTML template(ERB)

Web Developer I Rexholiday

Taipei, Taiwan I July 2013 to December 2013

- · Collaborated with stakeholders to improve an internal traveling system
- · Developed internal IT devices plan
- · Enhanced colleagues' workflow using SaaS

Web Developer I Webike.tw

Taipei, Taiwan I January 2013 to July 2013

- Designed and developed the first version of prototype of eCommerce website base on Magento
- Organized over 300k primitive data to MySQL database
- Deployed project to EC2 instances in LAMP environment on AWS
- · Made back-up plans and optimized servers' performances

Education

Diploma in Computer Programmer Seneca College - Toronto, ON

Bachelor in Information management Hsing Wu University - Taipei, Taiwan

Activity

Volunteer I Fa-Yi Chong-De Guang-Hui Association

Toronto, Canada I April 2014 to Present

- Assisted members to run meetings using live streaming platform
- · Educated charity member on selection and implementation of electronic devices
- Organizing meeting records and distributed records to members

August 2007 to August 2011

Work experiences in detail

Front End Developer I University of Waterloo - Conrad Business Centre

Waterloo, Canada I May 2017 - Aug 2017

As my role as an F2E, In my current project, React and Redux is the major framework we are using.

The major part I charge include creating/enhancing components by using React and Redux.

In this case, our backend is serverless structure, so that I have a chance to understander what the serverless structure is. I also have experience with calling and dealing with API service(3rd API such as Twilio's chatting service).

In addition, I built the end-2-end testing by Mocha and Selenium. In the testing process, it goes through all features we have made by various browsers automatically.

React:

- Create scalable components as much as I can.
 - e.g. Think about if components can be displayed variably by just receiving props rather than make components which are very similar to others.
- · Concept of separating components clearly
 - e.g. A complex component should be divided many sub-components rather than compose all components into one.
 - Usually, I separate each component as a single .js file. That's easy to maintain to me.
- · Familiar with life cycles, understand life cycles and use them in various situations.
 - For different purposes, I know how to use life cycles to trigger functions or get the data.
- · Familiar with dealing Async
 - In some situations, the UI components can be triggered by states which might be generated by Async.

Redux:

- · Familiar with various data structure
 - e.g. If we want to search a specific from a sequence, we can consider making Hashmap sequence which is faster and easy to manipulate data.
 - So, depends on the purpose, I am able to design scalable data structure.
- Separate business logic and UI
 - · Create business logic to actions in Redux.
 - The actions must be designed base on business logic rather than UI structure.
 - i.e. A great designed action, it should be able to be called/triggered by any UI components, not just only specific one.
- · Middleware/ redux-thunk /Async
 - Redux-thunk to deal with Async cases is my major approach.

I use React and Redux to develop features for most of them. Basically, I am in charge all UI components, but the following features are the major features I've done.

Real-time chatting room:

- · We use Twilio's message service as our comment and real-time chatting features
- · Enhanced UX by creating autoscrolling
- Able to detect new messages and scroll to the end of the window to show the newest content to the users.

Learning module:

- · Layout components by flex attribute
- · Allows to use keyboard shortcuts to change slides like www.slideshare.net
- · Combined with the comment feature

Analytic:

- Rendering tracking data as visualization graph by using Recharts.
- · Optimized data first before rendering graphs
- · Customize the select bar to be fancy by using React-select
- Enhanced UX and UI to be easy to select users to display the graph.